Now, of course we can't really expect the Lookup Table method to work all the time.
当然查询表不可能始终有用
Here's a new example where the sentences are getting a bit more complicated.
再举一个新的示例 这次的句子更加复杂
Now, our data is formed by the sentences,
数据由以下句子组成
Mary will see Jane,
Mary will see Jane.
Will will see Mary,
Will will see Mary
and Jane will see Will.
以及 Jane will see Will.
And the tags are as follows.
标记是这样的
Noun, modal, and verb.
名词 情态动词 动词
And our goal is to tag the sentence,
我们的目标是标记句子：
Mary will see Will.
Mary will see Will.
So we do a normal Lookup Table like this,
我们正常地创建一个查询表
and let's tag our sentence.
开始标记句子
Mary gets correctly tagged as a noun.
Mary 正确地标记为名词
Then Will, get correctly tagged as a modal.
will 正确地标记为情态动词
See gets correctly tagged as a verb,
see 正确地标记为动词
and here's a problem.
现在遇到问题了
Will, always get tagged as a modal since it
Will 始终标记为情态动词
appears three times as modal and two times as a noun,
因为有三次出现为情态动词 两次出现为名词
but in this sentence, we know Will is a noun since it's referring to our friend Will.
但是在这个句子中 我们知道 Will 是名词 因为它指的是好友 Will
This is a problem. In particular,
这就是一个问题
Lookup Tables won't work very well if a word can have two different tags,
具体而言 如果某个单词有两种不同的标签 则查询表不太好使
since it will always pick the most common tags that's
因为无论语境如何
associated with no matter the context.
它始终会选择最常见的相关标记
So now the question is,
现在的问题是
how do we take the context into account?
如何考虑语境
Well, the simplest way to think of context is to look at each words neighbor.
最简单的方法是查看每个单词的邻近单词
So for instance, if we tag pairs of words.
例如可以对单词对进行标记
For example, here we tagged the consecutive pair,
我们将连续单词对
see-Jane as a verb-noun one time,
see-Jane 标记为动词-名词一次
as it appears once as verb-noun.
因为它出现为动词-名词一次
And now, onto tag other sentence.
现在开始标记其他句子
We'll tag the first word using the previous table.
使用之前的表格标记第一个单词
So let's tag Mary as a noun.
将 Mary 标记为名词
Now, for each following word,
对于后续每个单词
we'll tag using the previous one,
我们将使用前一个单词和查询表
and the Lookup Table to find the pair of tags that correspond to them.
查找对应的标记对
So for example, to tag the word will,
例如 要标记单词 will
we look at Mary-will in particular where Mary is
我们看看 Mary-will 其中 Mary 是名词
a noun and we see that the most common one is when will is a modal.
最常见的情形是 will 是情态动词
So we'll tag will as a modal.
因此将 will 标记为情态动词
We continue tagging see as a verb,
继续将 see 标记为动词
and the second Will correctly as a noun,
将第二个 Will 正确地标记为名词
since the pair see-Will is tagged as a verb-noun.
因为单词对 see-Will 被标记为动词-名词
Notice that I was a bit vague with this algorithm.
注意我在介绍这个算法时比较模糊
The reason is there are many ways to define the details here,
因为有很多定义细节的方式
and most of them work well.
大多数方式都效果不错
I encourage you to think of ways to refine this.
建议你思考一些完善该算法的方式
For example, let's say you're tagging a word based on itself and the previous one,
例如 可以根据单词本身和前一个单词进行标记
and your Lookup Table actually corrects the tagging of the previous word,
查询表会纠正前一个单词的标记
do you keep the existing one, or use the new one?
你是保留现有标记 还是使用新的标记？
These are all decisions that are based on what fits the data best.
这些都是在考虑什么方式最适合数据时需要作出的决策
Of course, Bigrams are not the end of the story,
当然 双字母组并不是唯一方式
we can do it with three words at a time or even more.
一次还可以查看三个单词 甚至更多
These are called Ingrams and they're also very good with part of speech tagging.
这些称之为 Ingram 非常适合词性标注